This is where we left off in the previous video, we have nicely organized
这是上次的视频最后讲到的地方，我们已经学过
our worksheet and we are
整理工作表，现在我们开始学习怎么计算利润。
calculating the profit, the potential profit that we could make
利润也就是通过出售我们的股份
by selling all of our shares. But of course, now that we
所赚到的潜在盈利。 当然，现在我们已经
have added this Trend column, we want to do something with it.
添加了这个趋势列（Trend column），那么我们就要用它做些事情。
We don't want to sell all our shares
假如股价上涨，我们就不会卖掉这些股票。
if the price is going up, so we want to make a calculation -
所以我们需要根据这一趋势做一些计算，
based on a trend, we will make a decision are we selling
由此来决定我们将要卖
or are we not selling. So how does this look like?
还是不卖这些股票。 那么，这该怎么做呢？
We will add another column in this worksheet,
我们将在这个工作表里添加另一列
now we're going to call it the Number or the Amount that we're going to sell,
根据趋势，把这一列规定为要卖的数量Number
based on the trends. So let's add another column "Amount to sell"
或总量Amount。 因此，让我们添加另一列 “Amount to sell”
and then here we will use
然后我们将使用
a conditional formula, the IF formula, and that works as following:
一个条件公式， IF公式，它是这样设定的：
the first part of the IF formula says what are we going to look at,
条件(if)公式的第一个部分告诉我们要查看的是什么地方。
so we say: if the Trend, the G column,
所以我们说：如果这趋势（在G列），
is equal to "Up", in that case, after the comma, we say
等于上涨“Up”，在这种情况下， 逗号之后，我们指定
what we are doing. Well, if the trend is going up,
我们将要做的操作。 好吧，如果趋势是 上涨，
we're not selling anything, we're selling 0 shares.
我们将不卖任何东西，或者说卖掉 0股。
In the other case, if the trend is going down,
在另一种情况下，比如，趋势是下跌的，
let's say we sell half of our shares. We still remain with half of it, but we want to
那我们就要卖掉一半的股票。 但我们仍然还持有一半。这是为了安全起见，
sell half just to be safe,
我们只想卖掉一半股票，
if things are going wrong. And you see now, in the first line,
以防发现这些趋势不对。 现在你们看，在第一行中，
we're not selling anything and in subsequent lines,
我们不卖任何东西，但接着这一行后，
in case the shares are going down, yes, we are selling some,
万一股票是下跌的，那么， 我们就卖掉一些，
half of the shares that we have. And what I can do now here to round,
持有的一半股票。 而我现在可以在这里做，
as we've done in the previous video, is I could set it to 0 decimals,
正如我们在以前的视频做的，就是 可以将其设置为0位小数。
because I don't want, of course, to sell half of share, that's not possible.
当然，因为我不想卖掉一半的股份，那是不可能的。
But what I could also do here instead is use the ROUND function, it has the same
但我在这里可以做的，是使用ROUND函数代替，它具有相同的
function and works the same. Some people prefer to use ROUND function because it
功能和运用起来也差不多。 有些人喜欢用ROUND函数，
is more clear
因为它对究竟发生了什么更加了如指掌
what exactly is going on. You can see in the formula
你可以在公式里看到
that something is being rounded,
有些是要被四舍五入的，
and still our data is connected to the web feed,
而且我们的数据是连接到Web Feed的，
so if we hit Refresh and if something would have changed in the meantime,
因此，如果我们点击刷新，如果之前做了修改，
everything in the worksheet changes - so the data, and the formulas, and then
所有工作表内的东西都会变 -数据丶公式，
also, ultimately, the decision of how much shares we are going to sell.
还有最后我们打算卖出多少股票的决定。
Maybe you notice now that's something is wrong in this worksheet.
也许你注意到现在这工作表里有地方错了 。
Maybe you are
也许你正对着电脑数据大喊：
yelling at your computer stream: "Wait, wait, I found a mistake!"
“等等丶等等， 我发现了一个错误！“
Do you know what? This profit column is now based
你知道这个错误是什么吗？ 这个利润列现在是基于
on the number of shares that I
我所拥有的全部股票数量
have all of them. But, if I'm not selling all of them, of course I'm
但是，如果我不是卖掉所有股票，当然我
also not going to make profit out of all of them.
也不会卖掉所有的股票来收益。
So what I need to do is update my formula not to be calculated based
因此，我需要做的就是更新我的 公式，让它不是基于我所持有的总股票数量来计算
on the shares I have, but on the shares that I'm going to sell
而是基于趋势计算出来的
based on the trends. And what happens now here
我所要卖的数量。 那么，现在这里会发生就是
is that this profit is depending on the column left
利​​润取决于 左右两边列吗？
and right to it, and that's not something we like - if we talk about
这也不是我们想要的 - 如果我们讨论的是
organizing your worksheet, we want the data to flow nicely through your spreadsheet
整理工作表，我们会希望 数据流会从左到右的，
from left to right. So I swapped those two columns and now the flow is nicely
很好的排列在电子表格里。 所以我把这两列做一个交换。
logical
现在，当你从左往右读时，数据很完美地呈现出来，
as you would read it normally, from left to right. So that's also
并且非常合乎逻辑。 所以，这也是你在设计你自己的电子表格时
an organization factor that you can take into account when
可以考虑的一个组织管理方面
So there's one more thing that we want to do - what we want to do is calculate
此外，还有我们要做的另外一件事——
the health of the portfolio that we have. So I want to know
计算我们投资组合的优质程度。 如果我想知道
do I have a lot of Up shares and a lot of Down shares,
我是不是持有太多下跌的股票或上涨的股票
because if a big part of my portfolio is going down,
因为如果在投资组合里很大部分都下跌的时候，
maybe I want to make some other decisions - I want to buy additional shares
可能我想要做些其它的决定 -
that are going up. So what I could do potentially is:
想要购买更多正在上涨的股票。 所以，我能做的事情有：
I could use another conditional formula as you see here.
用另一种条件 公式，如你在这里看到的。
I could say: if the shares are going up then
我可以说：如果股票上涨
I want to have the number of shares, and otherwise I have 0. And then, in one
那么我就要拥有某一数量的股票份数， 否则我就持有0份。 然后，在这一列里
I get a list of all the shares
我有一份全部上涨的股票名单
that are going up. And I could do the exact same thing for down,
对下跌的股票，我也可以进行同样的操作，
same function: if the shares are going down,
一样的函数：如果股票下跌，
if the trend is equal to "Down", then
也就是趋势等于“下跌DOWN”，
I pick the number of shares, and otherwise I pick 0.
我将选出的某一数量的股票， 否则我挑0。
And then have two columns in which one is all the Up shares
然后可以建立两列，其中一列所有股票上涨
and the other is all the Down shares. And then, of course, I guess you understand
另一列全部下跌。 接下来，我猜你们能理解下面的操作
at the end of the worksheet I can add a SUM
在工作表的一端添加 一个SUM函数，
function and then I get an overview of the health of my portfolio,
然后我就可以大概知道我的投资组合的优异度，
what part of it is going up and what part of it
里面的哪些是上涨的，
is going down. Let's see how it looks like - I'm going to sum
哪些是下跌的 让我们来看看结果如何吧-
the entire column, there we go.
我现在要把整列相加，开始吧。
So 1800 shares going up, and if I drag it, about 700 shares going down.
所以，1800股上升，如果我拖下这里，约700股是下跌的。
So, our portfolio looks pretty okay because a lot more shares are going up than
因此，我们的投资组合看起来很不错，因为上涨的股票，
that are going down. However, this calculation is wrong - you need
比下跌的多。 但是，这个计算是不对的 - 你还需要
two additional columns and two additional
另外两个附加列和另外两个
SUM formulas just to get an idea of
SUM公式来知道数据走向的情况
how things are going. This can be done
这可以用一个简单的方法做到
in an easier way and let me show you how. So let's zoom out a little bit,
让我演示给你看怎么操作。 因此，让我们稍微放大一点
then you see all the extra information, all the extra space that we need,
然后你可以看到我们需要的所有的额外信息和 额外的空间。
two extra columns just to calculate these three
增加两个额外列只是为了计算这三個值，
values, that are Up and Down. So let's not do it,
就是UP与Down。 所以，我们不需要这么做，
let's clear this room, we're going to do it away with it, we don't need it anymore.
让我们把这清理下，我们要把它们删掉，我们不需要使用它们了。
Right click, "Clear Contents", there we go,
点击右键，选择“清除内容”，可以了，
we don't need it anymore. Let me show you a better
我们再也不需要它了。 让我告诉你一个更好
and a way more compact way to actually analyse
和更简洁的方式来实际分析
the health of our portfolio. What we can use
我们的投资组合优异度。 我们 可以使用
is a list of all the types, so we say we're looking for
的是所有类型股票的列表，也就是 我们
shares that are going up and shares that are going down. And then we use a SUMIF
正在上涨的股票，和正在下跌的股票。 然后我们使用SUMIF函数
function. It's a combination of,
顾名思义，
of course, the SUM and the IF. And how this function works is that I can
它就是SUM和IF的结合。 这个函数的功能就是我可以
pick part of my spreadsheet, so I click one column
挑我的电子表格的某一部分 ，所以我点击这一列，
and I say I'm going to look at everything that matches in that
我将看到这一列里所有相符合条件的数据
column. So where am I going to look is the first part of the function.
因此，我要注意的地方是这个函数的第一部分。
In the Trend column I'm going to look if
在趋势列Trend column中，我要看看
something is going on, like with the normal IF.
是否会有结果发生，就像一般情况下的IF函数。
Well, what do I need to compare to
那么，我只需要把它同IF函数做比较
is exactly the same as in the
和IF函数完全一样
IF function - I'm comparing is the Trend
- 我要比较的是趋势
equal to "Up" and I've just made a list of this. And what am I summing -
也就是“上涨UP”还有我刚刚做的这一个列表。 我现在真正累计总和的是
the number of shares. And you see me drag down,
股票的数量 你看我下拉这里，
and the exact same result is appearing,
显示出来的是完全相同的结果，
as when we had the entire column with the SUMs.
和我们给整列做总和的结果一样。
So it's a lot conciser and also it allows us for
所以这个（sumif）函数更加简洁，并且还能 让我们
easily adding other types of trends - for instance we have a "Flat" trend
轻松添加其他类型的趋势 - 例如，现在有一个“平稳（FLAT）”的趋势
where nothing is changing, we can just add "Flat" to list
不需要做修改，我们只要在列表里 加上“平稳（FLAT）“
and drag the formula down, whereas in the old situation
并且只要下拉公式就可以。
we needed an extra column for every new share type. So the SUMIF
然而在之前的情况中，我们需要给每个新的股票类型新增一个额外的列。 所以SUMIF
is a really nice combination of the SUM and the IF
是 SUM和IF的功能完美结合的函数
that takes up a lot less space and is more flexible
占用的空间更小，也更灵活
if you want to change your worksheets. So, this week we've looked at an example
如果你想更改你的工作表。 那么，本周我们学习了电子表格操作的一个例子，
where we're calculating the value of stocks, we've looked at functions to manipulate
在这个例子中我们学习了如何计算股票的价值， 我们学习了处理Strings与text values的函数
text values, we've looked at conditional formulas, the IF
我们也学了条件 公式，IF和
and the SUMIF, and piece everything together with the data taken
SUMIF，并且对网上找来的数据进行了分析
from the web. So that's everything we want
所以，这是我们
to talk about this week, just one more thing -
这个星期要谈论 的，再多说一件事 -
let me ask you once more to post your excelfies
再次提醒下大家把 excelfies发布
on the forum, so we have an idea of who we're working with.
在论坛上，这样我们就可以知道我们在和谁打交道。
See you next week!
让我们下周见！